Nancy Hale Papers, 1908-1989
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES VII. WRITINGS
  - Books, [see also volumes on shelf]
    - Untitled novel (unpublished)
      - Research material: printed pamphlets on Unitarianism (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Unidentified fragments and notes undated (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Cassettes
    [see Charlieshope and A Relating above]
    - Charlieshope: notes for rewrite (Box 65)
    - A Relating: The Personal Record of a Black Virginia Girlhood: taped conversations between Annie Richardson and Nancy Hale (Box 65)
- VOLUMES (on shelf)
  - Beyond the Dark and the Daylight. NY: Charles Scribners' Sons 1943
  - Dear Beast Boston: Little, Brown & co. 1959. Inscribed "To Helen Arnold with much love Nancy Hale"
  - The Earliest Dreams. NY: Charles Scribners' Sons 1936 Inscribed "To Charles with my love, Nancy Hale"
  - The Empress's Ring. NY: Charles Scribners' Sons 1955
  - Mary Cassatt. Garden City, NY: Doubleday & Co., Inc. 1975 Inscribed "For Clara Perkins Stites with much love from her old friend Nancy Hale"
  - Nancy Hale: On the Life and Work of a Lost American Master. Warrensburg, MO: Pleiades Press 2012
  - A New England Girlhood. Boston: Little, Brown & Co., first edition [1958]. Inscribed "To my darling Liddy who nurtured most of these with love from Nancy Hale, May 1958" 1958
  - New England Discovery: A Personal View. (NY: Coward-McCann, Inc. 1963
  - The Night of the Hurricane NY: Coward, McCann & Geoghegan, Inc. 1978
  - The Prodigal Women. Garden City, NY: The Sun Dial Press 1943
  - The Prodigal Women with an introduction by Mary Lee Settle. Plume American Women Writers Series, NY: New American Library 1988
  - Secrets. NY: Coward, McCann & Geoghegan, Inc.1971
  - The Sign of Jonah. NY: Charles Scribner's Sons 1950 Inscribed "To Mrs. Arnold who has always been such a romantic and fascinating figure to me. With love from Nancy Hale"
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL
    - Awards
      - Sarah Josepha Hale award 1974 (Box 66)
      - Virginia Cultural Laureate medal 1981 (Box 66)
    - Clippings scrapbook 1930s (Box 66)
    - Drawings by Nancy Hale undated (Box 67)
  - SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE
    - Pugh, Gracie and Cresson 29 Aug 1973 (Box 66)
  - SERIES IV. PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Nancy Hale
      - 1930s (Box 66)
      - 1940s (Box 66)
      - 1950s-60s (Box 66)
    - Nancy Hale and Taylor Scott Hardin wedding 1928 (Box 66)
    - Winsor School class of 1926, 1926 (Box 66)
  - SERIES VII. WRITINGS
    - Children's Stories: first proof of illustration for "Birds in the House" by Mary Louise Ehrenpreis 7 Jan 1985 (Box 66)